<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Marine Ecology &amp; Data Science</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Marine Ecology &amp; Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science teaching resources</title>
      <link>/2018/10/03/data-science-teaching-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/03/data-science-teaching-resources/</guid>
      <description>In my new role as lecturer at Hopkins Marine Station, I am in the process of brainstorming my upcoming courses. One of these is &amp;lsquo;Environmental Data Science&amp;rsquo;, and as I was writing out the course schedule, I began to appreciate the dilemma of fitting in the appropriate mix of modern data carpentry skills with more traditional statistics requirements within the constraints of a 10 week schedule. One could make the case that these should be two separate courses, but that&amp;rsquo;s another issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting marine socio-environmental covariates (MSEC) from a netcdf file</title>
      <link>/2018/09/07/extracting-marine-socio-environmental-covariates-msec-from-a-netcdf-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 12:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/09/07/extracting-marine-socio-environmental-covariates-msec-from-a-netcdf-file/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I am working on a project that is trying to understand why some coral reefs are faring better than others. Towards this end, I am collating a number of predictors hypothesized to influence the condition of coral reefs. In this post, I am going to demonstrate the steps necessary to take advantage of the awesome MSEC (marine socio-environmental covariates) dataset by Yeager et al. 2017.
There are two ways to go about extracting the geospatial data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctors without binders - data science consulting as an Insight Fellow</title>
      <link>/2018/06/26/doctors-without-binders---data-science-consulting-as-an-insight-fellow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 21:49:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/26/doctors-without-binders---data-science-consulting-as-an-insight-fellow/</guid>
      <description>Physicians are overburdened by their binders full of paperwork. Consequently, doctors are often staring at their computer screen instead of interacting with their patient. In fact, the burden is so great that a new profession - medical scribe - has emerged. Medical scribes accompany physicians and manually transcribe their conversations and enter annotated notes into the electronic medical record. Bank and Gage (2015) demonstrated that cardiovascular physicians with scribes:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>